dr. O'Connor this video is about
Dianabol what is Diana ball
Diana ball is the first oral anabolic
steroid produced in the world known as
the breakfast of champions
it goes back to 1955 when it was first
described the generic name of Dyna ball
is meth and roastin alone and this
classic historic story is that a team
positioned for the u.s. Olympics named
John Ziegler witnessed the Russians in
1956 at a competition having problems as
they were using testosterone suspension
in her muscular injections with urinary
retention and he actually witnessed
supposedly in the vac training area one
of their athletes having to be catheter
categorized because his prostate was
enlarged from the use of testosterone
derivatives so that's where it started
he went back though from this training
1956-57 and he was interested in using
and producing some of these agents
called anabolic steroids and no one knew
they weren't really called them at that
time but he thought that he would want
to use an agent like this and so he
started to work with a pharmaceutical
company named Seba and he did that and
in 1958 he produced Dianabol with with
steve-o and at that time they introduced
it into the market in 1958 and what they
did was they produce the first oral
steroid from testosterone derivatives
that were produced and discovered really
back of in late 1930s 1940s they were
using suspension testosterone suspension
and they realized that they were were
anabolic versus androgenic effects and
the angiogenic effects are male
secondary sex aspects that can be
enhanced by these drugs visualization if
you will and that's what they thought
led to the prostate enlargement
so they wanted to minimize that they
wanted to maintain the anabolic effects
this is the anabolic steroid science and
they want to minimize the angiogenic
effects so they did that by the classic
seventeen alpha alkylation and that's
what made an oral anabolic steroid in
that day interestingly enough this
steroid is also produced in veterinary
type methodologies with inter muscular
liquid suspensions and it's since been
made actually in drop of formations
that's it's counterfeited all over the
world and so that's the 1958 went to the
market pen ten years later 1967 or so
dr. Ziegler condemned the use of this
drug because he saw over a ten-year
period that it was massively abused and
he must have actually had regrets
himself I think in historical remarks
and books on dr. Ziegler he regrets
being part of this and producing this
anabolic steroid that today is still one
of the most widely used massive and
above steroids in the world by 1983 cybo
withdraws in the US market secondary to
the fact that the the US government was
asking for documentation for medical
purposes of this drug and they really
couldn't come up with any at that time
except for treating people that had
catabolic States and even osteoporosis
and women but the side effects
obviously placed this medication into a
point that it currently stands today
obviously where the side effects far
outweigh the any possible medical
benefits dr. O'Connor tell us what are
the benefits of Dianabol so the benefits
of an oral or inner muscular anabolic
steroid obviously are going to be muscle
preserving muscle building and it does
it stands today that we need to work on
developing an agent for people that are
suffering from muscle
facing diseases either from cancer and
cachexia and the standard age-related
sarcopenia condition for as people get
older they become Sarco pinna canned
they lose muscle mass they become weak
all people fall and they can't get up so
those are the benefits it's straight
muscle building so how much muscle and
strength can one user gain on Dianabol
well Dianabol is that's the
old-fashioned drug that's even still
used today so Dianabol initially by the
manufacturing grade recommendations was
two point five five and maybe ten
milligrams a day using back there is
great gains on that actually amazingly
the gains itself are dose dependent and
it can go up now to today where it's up
to thirty to fifty milligrams a day and
even more obviously the side effects are
going to be horrible and great gains
unbelievable muscle gains I mean this is
the medicine that people use
independently or with other steroids and
you gain mass you gain strength and size
all the power two-thirds that come to
see me across the world for over a
decade as I do what I do is an expert in
anabolic steroids is you see that the
initiation is always with Dianabol so
talking about side effects tell us more
about that so this is the problem with
with oral and about steroids or inter
muscular steroids that the side-effect
profile can be horrific
obviously dose dependent and man per man
depended not to mention women have side
effects - side effects are secondary to
the aromatization secondary to the
shutdown of the hypothalamus pituitary
go enact axis secondary to the the oral
aspects of the 17 alpha alkylation and
the paddle toxicity and secondary to the
side effects in the coronary artery
potential progression and what it can do
to the heart and the endothelial blood
vessel disease
through multiple mechanisms where it can
cause hypertension it can cause fluid
edema again unknown if that secondary to
aromatization this is a drug that is
very strong aromatize a drug where it
converts estrogen you can get puffy that
can lead to all sorts of medical issues
and hypertension and degradation of
issues with the heart cardiovascular
system not to mention the urinary system
it is less androgenic than testosterone
but it's still angiogenic and you're
still gonna have gynecomastia still
gonna have hair loss and affection the
prostate I've seen men with significant
urinary tract issues from this drug
alone staying out of all legal
dinoball is definitely not legal
obviously since it was withdrawn from
the market in the United States 1983 and
then subsequently other steroids were
removed in the 1990s and in America
there has been a ban essentially and
where they made anabolic steroids a
controlled drug and you have a rate
limitation for how we can use these
mainly for hypogonadism for male
hypogonadism is testosterone derivatives
so it's absolutely not legal in America
and it's not legal in most countries in
the world and it's not legal not because
of the cheating it's it's not legal
because of the danger medical dangerous
last question dr. O'Connor
how much does Dianabol cost dinoball is
actually one of the cheapest anabolic
steroids produced in the world the raw
ingredients are actually very simple to
make supposedly and it will be flooding
to the market because it's very cheap
and it's very effective so that's a very
good question thank you dr. O'Connor
thank you